Hi, this is Sean Hobson.
Right now we're working with our post players, giving them some moves that they can use to be successful and be scorers in our offense.
One move we're going to talk about right now is called the up and under move.
And usually this is used when the defender is playing on the bottom side, and he's forcing this guy to turn into the middle, because he knows that he's already got a good drop step, so we're trying to take his drop step away and make him one dimensional, which means that this post player's going to have to catch the ball and he's going to have to spin inside to face the basket because the bottom side is taken away.
So, we've got a move called the up and under move.
So what he's going to do this time is he's going to catch the ball, we're going to kind of walk through this together.
He's going to catch the ball, he's going to spin first of all and face up the basket.
Now when he does that, this guy's going to jump out to block his shot.
What he's going to do then with the same foot that he pivoted with, he's going to pivot around, he's going to shot fake him, as this guy shot fakes and gets off balance, then he's going to step through with the same foot, and he can power dribble now, power dribble, get that other foot and a hop so that he can face up and he can make that shot.
It's kind of a complicated move, but if you work at it slow and then speed it up, you become much better at it.
So you're going to pivot, fake, step through with the same foot you pivoted with, power dribble, hop, and score.
You might want to right that down and go through those sequences together.
We're going to show you what it looks like at full speed here.
All right, here we go.
Good, shot fake, takes it to the hole, and scores it.
And that's called the up and under move.
That move alone right there will separate good players from the lower players.
So if you can learn that move, you're going to be at the higher caliber of all the centers.